

Technology and Impact Executive

Science | Culture | Education

+1 352 537 8375

scottbot.net

weingart.scott@gmail.com

~

South Bend, IN and Washington, DC

# ELEVATING EXPERTS TO BUILD A VIBRANT FUTURE

Three-time inaugural director of initiatives that last, using evidence-based approaches to build infrastructures in support of thriving organizations and communities. Over a decade of leadership experience across academic, service, and government sectors. Multihyphenate expert, with experience as a federal technology executive, the elected treasurer of a multinational nonprofit, an award-winning scholar and author, and a juggler who has performed professionally around the world.

## EDUCATION

2019

#### **MSc Data Science**

Indiana University Bloomington
School of Informatics & Computing

2009

BA History of Science Minor Computer Engineering

University of Florida

# EXPERIENCE

#### Leadership

Change Management
Financial Management (\$10m+)
Fundraising (Raised \$16m+)
International Event Organization
Nonprofit Board Membership
Policymaking
Servant Leadership
Strategic Planning

#### Academic & Library

Curriculum Development
Digital Archiving & Preservation
Digital Publishing
Collection Development
Public Speaking (Int'l Keynotes)
Research (Humanistic, Qual, & Quant)
Resource Management
Service Coordination
Teaching

Writing (Public, Scholarly, & Technical)

# WORK HISTORY

### **National Endowment for the Humanities**

Jan 2023 - now

#### Federal Chief Data Officer (Inaugural)

Executive and policy maker responsible for data infrastructure across the federal agency; evidence-informed decision making; research and data analysis; and performance measurement. Keep the United States public informed of the state and value of the humanities.

- <u>Leadership</u>. Direct the Office of Data and Evaluation. Advise presidential appointees.
   Shape policies impacting \$170 million in national initiatives. Partner in strategic planning.
- <u>Technologies</u>. Build and oversee master data management plan and artificial intelligence capacity, ensuring agency operations remain smooth, nimble, and forward-facing.
- Programs. Direct multimillion-dollar grantmaking and contracting program.
- <u>Partnerships</u>. Build partnerships and coalitions with other federal agencies, private philanthropies, and non-profits. Represent NEH on Federal Chief Data Officer Council.

#### **University of Notre Dame**

Mar 2021 - Dec 2022

Navari Family Center for Digital Scholarship Director (Inaugural)

Senior leader directing a center charged with preparing researchers across the university for tomorrow's emerging technologies and advanced computational methods.

- Associate librarian and faculty affiliate of Lucy Family Institute for Data & Society.
- Served on the Library Cabinet (senior administrative body of Hesburgh Libraries).
- Oversaw strategic planning assessments related to digital and technical strategy.

Details of the Navari Family Center for Digital Scholarship:

- 11,500 ft<sup>2</sup>, \$10+ million endowed research and service center.
- 15+ faculty and staff (including the heads of Architecture and Business branch libraries).
- Services including scientific cloud computing environment; data science support; hardware and software lending library; research data management, and fellowship program.
- Specialized facilities including a makerspace, VR room, legacy video game and technology collection, tech-enriched classrooms, computer lab, and a data visualization wall.

## EXPERIENCE

#### **Technical**

Cybersecurity

Cloud Computing (AWS / Azure)

Data Governance

Data Management

**Data Modeling** 

**Data Security** 

**Data Visualization** 

Database Design & Querying

Deep Learning / Artificial Initelligence

Docker & Kubernetes

Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP)

High Performance Computing

IT Support & Helpdesk

**Ontology Development** 

PowerBI & Tableau

Scientific Coding (R/Python)

**Technical Strategy** 

**UX** Design

Web Coding (HTML/CSS/JS)

## Methodological

3D Modeling & Fabrication

Agent-Based Modeling

Bayesian & Frequentist Statistics

Citation Analysis

GIS & Web Mapping

Machine Learning & Linear Algebra

Natural Language Processing

Network Science

#### Grantmaking

Compliance Monitoring

**Evidence-Informed Philanthropy** 

**Grant Operations & Processing** 

Program Development

**Program Evaluation & Assessment** 

# SCHOLARSHIP

Author of two books and dozens of publications spanning the humanities, social sciences, and natural sciences. Collectively, these have been translated into eight languages and cited more than 3,500 times. Recipient of prestigious Paul Fortier Prize in Digital Humanities.

# WORK HISTORY (CONTINUED)

#### **Carnegie Mellon University**

Feb 2015 - Mar 2021

Digital Humanities Program

Director (Inaugural)

Leader directing a \$2 million library-centered program to make CMU globally recognized for its computationally- and statistically-sophisticated humanities research initiatives.

- Managed faculty, developers, students, and interns on dozens of digital projects.
- Administered \$100k/year internal grant and fellowship program.
- Designed and implemented technical infrastructure supporting research across campus.

#### **Stanford University**

Jun 2014 - Dec 2014

#### **Data Scientist**

Developed technically innovative projects alongside scholars, librarians, and developers at Stanford University Libraries.

# Indiana University Research Associate

Jun 2009 - May 2014

Project managed scholars and developers to create scientific infrastructure, software, and documentation at the Cyberinfrastructure for Network Science Center.

# SELECTED OTHER ROLES

#### Sinai Synagogue

2024 - now

#### Chief Technology Officer

Volunteer technology lead overseeing computers, software, security system, sound system, and communication technologies.

#### University of Edinburgh

2023 - now

#### Research Affiliate

External affiliate researching and publishing on historiographic methods, the history of digital humanities, and other scholarly topics.

## Posen Library of Jewish Culture and Civilization

2022 - 2024

#### **Board Member**

Primary technical advisor on matters related to the redevelopment of Posen Library's web platform, digital publication chain, and online outreach strategy.

#### U.S. Copyright Office, Library of Congress

2021 - 2023

#### **Advisory Committee Member**

Public member of the Copyright Public Modernization Committee, advising on technology modernization of the U.S. Copyright Office and its associated data and service platforms.

#### **Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations**

2021 - 2022

#### Treasurer

Elected treasurer of multinational nonprofit and professional society, focused on migrating the organization from spreadsheet bookkeping to modern accounting software.